ANDREA C. BENTLEY

Duluth, GA 30096

Phone: 770-847-6763 | Email: <u>andrea@bentleytech.com</u> | Portfolio: <u>bentleytech.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/andrea-c-bentley</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/AndreaGT91</u>

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with seven years experience in accounting and healthcare software development and over a decade in education support. Strong drive to create applications that are user-friendly, efficient, adhere to established standards, and are easily maintainable. Known for being thorough, dependable, an exceptional collaborator, yet able to work independently. View coworkers as teammates, not competitors. Exemplary written and verbal communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Libraries/Frameworks: React.js, JSX, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Node.js, Express, SQL, Sequelize, Mongoose, AJAX, Jest, Handlebars

Applications: Git, npm, MySQL, MongoDB, Visual Studio Code, Terminal, Slack, Zoom, Microsoft Office products: Word, Excel, Power Point, Publisher, Outlook, and Access, Google Drive applications: Docs, Sheets, and Slides

EDUCATION

Certificate of Completion in Web Development: Georgia Tech Professional Education
Atlanta, GA
2020

Bachelor of Science in Information and Computer Science: *The Georgia Institute of Technology*With Honor, Cooperative Program, Certificate in Engineering Psychology
Atlanta, GA

RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer PACS Software

10/1995 - 09/1998

Alpharetta, GA

Redesigned legacy DOS-based Time and Billing application for Windows from the ground up using Delphi (object-oriented IDE for rapid application development) and TurboPower Orpheus.

Lead Engineer 06/1993 – 10/1995

Prentice Hall Professional Software

Smyrna, GA

Developed new features and updated business tax software with yearly tax law changes using Borland Pascal and TurboPower.

Software Analyst 06/1991 – 06/1993

Gerber Allev Norcross. GA

Analyzed client issues to find and solve software defects in hospital information system.

ADDITIONAL PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Registrar/Student Records Clerk

Pinckneyville Middle School

07/2016 – present

Peachtree Corners, GA

Register new students, process withdrawals, fulfill records requests, manage student files, maintain student/parent information in database, create database queries as needed.

Substitute Teacher

08/2009 - 05/2016

Gwinnett County Public Schools

Suwanee, GA

Filled in for Teachers (Regular and Special Ed), Paraprofessionals, Resource, Office/Clerical, and Clinic Worker.

Human Resources/Bookkeeper

08/2014 - 01/2015

North Metro Academy of Performing Arts

Norcross. GA

Processed payroll, coordinated employee benefits, paid bills, produced financial reports.

Lead Teacher/Assistant Teacher

08/2007 - 05/2010

Christ the King Preschool

Peachtree Corners, GA

Developed curriculum and lesson plans as lead teacher for one year, assisted lead teacher with implementing lessons for two years.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Foster

2020 – present

FurKids Animal Rescue and Shelter

Cumming, GA

Care for cats and kittens until they are ready to be adopted.

Troop Leader

2007 - 2020

Service Unit Registrar

2008 – 2013

Girl Scouts of Greater Atlanta, Inc. - Norcross Service Unit

Norcross. GA

Troop Leader: organized fun, interactive, girl-led activities to support and encourage girls to earn badges and high awards. Registrar: process all registrations from the Norcross area; developed Access database to maintain registration information; assisted with maintenance of organization's website.

Children's Ministries Volunteer

2004 - 2020

Simpsonwood United Methodist Church

Peachtree Corners, GA

Assisted with various roles in Vacation Bible School; taught Sunday School to various students; assisted Director with other projects, as needed.

PTA Volunteer

2004 – 2013

Simpson Elementary School

Peachtree Corners. GA

Coordinated parent volunteers for 5th grade musical and performed all necessary communication between Music Teacher and parents for the various Chorus performances. Volunteered in various roles, including Media Center, Reading Room, school-wide events, and classroom.

Alumna Adviser

1994 - 2000

Alpha Gamma Delta Fraternity, Gamma Phi Chapter, Georgia Tech

Atlanta, GA

Advised collegiate officers: VP Finance - coordinated financial audit and completed annual tax return; Activities Coordinator - ensured all necessary paperwork was complete for insurance purposes.